

# Stephanie Hekker

I'm an experienced software engineer with a track record for shipping large-scale, cloud-based, and production-ready services. My focus has been primarily in the backend using **Node.js** where I built and maintained a GDPR compliant API that parsed and stored real-time data into a data warehouse, then accessed by BI Engineers and other internal services, to run analytics. Frontend experience has leveraged **React**.

## **→■** Contact Information

stephanie.hekker@gmail.com



### Work Experience

#### The Crowd List

#### ➤ Founder & Software Engineer

August 2021 - Present

As a Founder and Software Engineer, I built a company that tracks all regulation crowdfunding campaigns in the United States. I designed and implemented the backend using **Node.js**, and **AWS Lambda** to leverage an **API**. On the frontend, I used a few no-code and automation tools such as **Airtable** and **Zapier**. I also write a weekly newsletter to a few hundred subscribers regarding equity crowdfunding. I have hired and trained contractors for manual database updates using async tools such as **Notion** and **Loom**.

[Tools Used]: Node.js, AWS Lambda, AWS Cron Events, Airtable, Zapier, Pory, Substack, Google Analytics

#### **Amazon**

#### ➤ Software Development Engineer

Alexa News (August 2018 - September 2020)

As an SDE, I designed, implemented (including unit tests, metrics, and alarms), and documented any service that I built. A significant majority of the services that I implemented were backend services built using **Node.js** though I also have experience delivering a frontend for one of our services using **React**. Within a team of 6 engineers, I was the SCRUM Master for our daily standup, facilitating team meetings regularly to assign tasks and track team progress.

A few of my notable projects include:

- A GDPR compliant backend service that parsed and logged real-time customer engagement data (JSON) and stored it in a redshift cluster. [Tools Used]: Node.js, AWS API Gateway, Lambda, SQS, Kinesis Firehose, and Redshift
- A backend service that fetched content (JSON or XML) via external APIs, parsed, and stored it. It was then accessed by our internal systems via an API. [Tools Used]: Node.js, AWS CRON, Lambda, S3, API Gateway
- A video content moderation website that called an API to get the videos and display them for our content moderation team to quickly determine if they were appropriate for our platform. [Tools Used]: React, AWS CloudFront, Lambda

Stephanie Hekker 1

#### **➤** Programmer

Amazon Technical Academy (September 2017 - July 2018)

I was selected as one of 28 employees (out of 1000+ applicants) to participate in Amazon's Technical Academy, an 11-month, full-time immersive software engineer training via lecture, daily assignments, projects, data structures and algorithms, and software design.

Notable Project:

Designed a Movie recommendation service with four APIs using Java, DynamoDB, API Gateway, and Lambda.

#### ➤ Quality Assurance Engineer

Customer Reviews (July 2013 - August 2017)

As a QAE, I collaborated with engineering managers in supporting dozens of engineers for product management while gathering knowledge and understanding of key features, user experience, and business goals. I oversaw test planning, test data creation, and testing for desktop and mobile projects; planned, documented, and executed 250+ tests per project using Jira, Rally, and TestRail. I wrote test automation using Java, Selenium Webdriver, TestNG, and Cucumber. I drove production releases using internal deployment and monitoring tools. I hired, trained, and mentored several new employees, including Quality Assurance Engineers. And last, but not least, I presented to over 100+ of my peers and leaders for an organization-wide career day to discuss the promotion path for Quality Assurance Engineers in 2016.





#### Javascript

I've used it in the backend for APIs with **Node.js**, in the frontend with **React**, and for testing automation using **Mocha** and **Chai**.

#### **Amazon Web Services**

Every production ready service that I've built used AWS Resources, including API Gateway, Lambda, S3, and Redshift.



My technical training is in Java. I used it both in my role as a QAE and as a Programmer.

### **Education**

#### B.A. in Business Administration - Management Information Systems

2005-2009

Western Washington University - Bellingham, WA

Stephanie Hekker 2